Maged Mohamed Mahmoud Youssef BADR

Address (Egypt): 8 Al Mahlawy st. Banha Al Gedida (Banha, Qalyoubia), Postal code Banha 13511.

Address (Canada): 9641 Simpson Place NW, Edmonton-Alberta.

Postal code: T6R 0T8

Tel. Cellular: +1 587-938-2425

E.Mails: maged_badr1980@yahoo.ca contact@magedbadr.com

The Profession

Spoken Languages:

Arabic: Mother Language.

English: Advanced.(IELTS 6.0).

French: Intermediate.(DELF B1) & TCF.

Written Languages:

Arabic : Mother Language.

English: Advanced.(IELTS 6.0)

French: Intermediate.(DELF B1) & TCF.

Career Objective:

Professional Medical Analysis Specialist (Chemist), has a great experience in the ability to manage all the medical analysis tests requirements, including ensuring that the organization standards meet legal compliance & Customer's Expectations.

I would like to join a medical facility or laboratory based in Canada.

Specific Skills:

- 1- Internet.
- 2- Auditing.
- 3- Photoshop.
- 4- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint).

The Studies:



1- From September 2012 to December 2013.

University: American University in Cairo

Place: Cairo, Egypt.

Degree: Post Graduate Diploma in Total Quality Management.

(TQM).

2- From September 2011 to December 2012

Institute:French Institute in Cairo.

Place: Cairo, Egypt.

Degree: Diploma in Bl level of the Common European Framework

of Reference for French Language (DELF B1).

3- From September 1997 to May 2001.

University: Banha University.

Place: Banha, Qalyoubia, Egypt.

Degree: BSc. in Microbiology & Chemistry from faculty of

Science.

4- From September 1994 to May 1997.

School: Al Manshia Military Secondary School.

Place: Banha, Qalyoubia, Egypt.

Degree :Diploma at the End of Secondary Studies.

Formations:

1 – From October 2013 to December 2013.

University: American University in Cairo.

Place: Cairo, Egypt.

Certificate: Managing the Quality Functions.

2 - From July 2013 to October 2013.

University: American University in Cairo.

Place: Cairo, Egypt.

Certificate: Project Management.

3 – From April 2013 to July 2013.

University: American University in Cairo.

Place: Cairo, Egypt.

Certificate: Statistical Quality Control.

4 – From February 2013 to April 2013.

University: American University in Cairo.

Place: Cairo, Egypt.

Certificate: The Basic Six Sigma Breakthrough Improvement Process.

5 – From December 2012 to February 2013.

University: American University in Cairo.

Place: Cairo, Egypt.

Certificate: Standards for Quality & Environmental Management.

System.

6 – From September 2012 to December 2012.

University: American University in Cairo.

Place: Cairo, Egypt.

Certificate: Planning for Top Quality.

Work Experience:

1- **Date**: From September 2014 till March 2016.

Position :Executive Manger. **Company :**Star Laboratory.

Website: www.star-laboratory.com
Location: Banha, Qalyoubia, Egypt

Postal Code: 13511 Egypt

Tasks: as follows:

1 - Developing and implementing various sales and distribution channels for the laboratory services.

- 2 Communicate with all stakeholders (internal and external) to achieve positive results.
- 3 Commitment Work is 7 hours Daily For Six Days Weekly for at least 42 hours Weekly with Full-time .
- 4 Plan and implement all marketing strategies aimed at attaining sales, market share and profitability growth for the laboratory within the overall marketing budgets.
- 5 Define the monthly and annual target.
- 6 Participate in planning and budgeting processes; personnel and equipment needs; develop and monitor laboratory budget.
- 7 Clarifying the instructions for each analysis professionally for patients.
- 8 Taking samples from patients professionally and preparing these samples to be analyzed in the Units.
- 9 Analyzing Microbiological, Biochemical, Hematological, Hormonal & PCR tests which are available in Banha Center units.
- 10 Reviewing and signing patients' results.
- 11 Delivering laboratories results and answering any Technical Inquiries.
- 12 Interviewing patients & reassuring them.
- 13 Replying doctors' inquiries.

2- Date: From July 2013 till September 2014.

Position: Banha Branch Manger.

Company: Al Borg Laboratories, Egypt.

Website: www.alborglab.com
Postal Code: 13511 Egypt

Location :Banha.

Tasks: as follows:

- 1 Developing and implementing various sales and distribution channels for the laboratory services.
- 2 Communicate with all stakeholders (internal and external) to achieve positive results.
- 3 Commitment Work is 7 hours Daily For Six Days Weekly for at least 42 hours Weekly with Full-time .
- 4 Plan and implement all marketing strategies aimed at attaining sales, market share and profitability growth for the laboratory within the overall marketing budgets.
- 5 Define the monthly and annual target.
- 6 Participate in planning and budgeting processes; personnel and equipment needs; develop and monitor laboratory budget.
- 7 Clarifying the instructions for each analysis professionally for patients.
- 8 Taking samples from patients professionally and preparing these samples to be analyzed in the Units.
- 9 Analyzing Microbiological, Biochemical and Hematological tests which are available in Branch units.
- 10 Reviewing and signing patients' results.
- 11 Delivering laboratories results and answering any Technical Inquiries.
- 12 Interviewing patients & reassuring them.
- 13 Replying doctors' inquiries.

3- Date: From November 2004 till July 2013.

Position : Medical Analysis Specialist. **Company :** Al Borg Laboratories, Egypt.

Website: www.alborglab.com

Location: Banha Branch.

Postal Code: 13511 Egypt

Tasks: as follows:

- 1 Performing Scientifically, Technical and Professional analysis in Branch Committed Rules applicable in medical analysis field and the foundation Rules developed for good performance of the company.
- 2 Commitment Work is 7 hours Daily For Six Days Weekly for at least 42 hours Weekly with Full-time.
- 3 Clarifying the instructions for each analysis professionally for patients.
- 4 Taking samples from patients professionally and preparing these samples to be analyzed in the Units.
- 5 Analyzing Microbiological, Biochemical and Hematological tests which are available in Branch units.
- 6 Reviewing and signing patients' results.
- 7 Delivering laboratories results and answering any Technical Inquiries.
- 8 Interviewing patients & reassuring them.
- 9 Replying doctors' inquiries.

Hobbies:

- 1 Internet.
- 2 Mobiles Applications.
- 3 Software Maintenance.

References on request:

1- Prof. Dr. Asmaa El Kholy.

Lecturer of Medical Parasitology

Faculty of Medicine - Banha University.

Cellulare: +2 012 24751144.

E.Mail: asmaa.alkholy@star-laboratory.com

Position: STAR Lab. CEO.

2 - Prof. Dr. Hisham Ali Eissa.

Professor of Clinical Pathology

Faculty of Medicine - Banha University.

Cellulare: +2 010 09120363.

E.Mail: hissa1966@yahoo.com

Position: Al Borg Lab. Technical Manager in Banha Branch.

3 - Prof. Dr. Basma Salem.

Lecturer of Clinical Patholgy.

Faculty of Medicine - Banha University.

Cellulare: +2 01012227881

E.Mail: basma.salem@star-laboratory.com

Position: STAR Lab. Technical Manager.

Edited in January 2016.